打扰一下  服务生
Excuse me, waitress?
抱歉我们不再提供照烧鸡了
I'm afraid the teriyaki chicken's no longer on the menu.
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
你上次点的是那个
That's what you had last time.
我们从没来过这
We've never been here before.
我确实记得你
I definitely remember you.
不  我们从没来过北边
No, we never get up north.
我们只是来看一个
We're just up to see a friend of ours
去年搬到这里的朋友
who moved here last summer.
那时你头发颜色更浅  还带着圆框眼镜
Your hair was lighter. You had little round glasses.
听上去像你
Sounds like you.
亨利  别听她的
Henry, don't play along.
她就是想骗点小费
It's a gimmick, for tips.
能给我们来杯水吗
Could we get some water?
那是去年八月  十四号  星期六
It was last August. Saturday, the 14th.
你穿着蓝底白点的裙子
You were wearing a blue dress with polka dots.
眼睛红肿
Your eyes were puffy,
好像刚哭过
like you'd been crying.
十四号是达伦的生日
The 14th is Darren's birthday.
他说他不得不取消生日聚会
He said he had to cancel his party
因为他的前女友来了
'cause his old girlfriend showed up.
他们大吵了一架
They got into a huge fight.
-亨利...  -我就知道  该死的
- Henry... - I knew it. Damn it.
从那次滑雪你俩无故消失时我就该知道的
Ever since that ski trip when the two of you disappeared.
我这就去  给你们倒水
I'll go...get your water.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
我的腿不能动了
I can't move my legs!
想象一扇门
Picture a door.
用思维之钥将其打开
Unlocked with the key of the mind.
两个病例  都比上次那个有趣的多
Two medical cases, both more fascinating than the last.
这一点逻辑都没有
That actually makes no logical sense.
那扇门不通向逻辑之路
This is not a door to logical sense.
还有  闭嘴
Also, shut up.
一号病例
Case number one.
33岁  女性
33-year-old woman
名字是...
Named...
我忘了
Something I can't remember.
你们一会就会发现讽刺之处了
You'll see the irony in a second.
症状表现为暂时性瘫痪
Presenting with temporary paralysis,
肌酸激酶水平过高
high CK levels,
以及完美的记忆力
and a perfect memory.
多完美算完美
How perfect is perfect?
完美无缺
Perfectly perfect.
超忆症
Hyperthymesia.
她能回忆起自青春期以来的
Complete recall of every moment of every day
所有时刻
since puberty.
全部760049分钟
All 7,600,049 of them.
很酷  是吧
It's cool, huh?
这是为数不多的记录在案的超忆病例之一
One of only a handful of recorded cases.
我们知道两个症状
So we have two symptoms:
暂时性腿部瘫痪以及肌酸激酶水平过高
Temporary leg paralysis and elevated CK.
看来你不是来自她的"超强记忆力星球"
Obviously you're not suffering from the same condition
因为你已然忘了我激动人心的画外音了
'cause you've already forgotten my dramatic voiceover.
还有第三个症状
There's a third symptom.
-她的记忆力与此无关  -为什么
- Her memory's unrelated. - Why?
这种医学现象十分罕见
It's a strange medical phenomenon--
超忆症一般在青春期显现
Hyperthymesia is known to manifest in adolescence.
就记录在案的五个病例而言  没错
Yeah, in the whole five documented cases.
如果有联系
To be related,
就意味着新的病症在二十年后才出现
it would mean 20 years between symptoms.
另外  我不知道什么病
Plus, I don't know of any diseases
会导致超强记忆力
that cause great memory.
只知道能破坏记忆的
Only ones that destroy it.
核磁共振显示没有中风或肿瘤的迹象
MRI showed no evidence of stroke or tumor,
可能是中毒
so probably a toxin.
她是服务员
She's a waitress.
服务员容易食物中毒和酗酒成性
They're no strangers to botulism or alcoholism.
我们应该检查下那家餐馆和她家里
We should search the diner and where she lives.
或者你们可以在她的脑中搜索
Or you could search her brain.
那里可是她的记忆之家
You know, where her memory lives.
省点油吧
Save the gas.
你们俩去检查她家
You two check her home.
你们俩去把病人的完整病史问出来
You two get a complete patient history.
看谁会先找到答案
We'll see who gets an answer first.
你不是说还有第二个病例吗
You said there's a second case?
啊  对了
Oh! Yeah.
多谢提醒
Thanks.
患者是一名45岁的医生
The case of the 45-year-old doctor
他没能通过病理学再认证考试
who just failed his pathology recertification exam
即将失去专科医学会认证资格
and is going to lose his board certification
还会被开除
and get fired.
你怎么会没通过
How'd you fail it?
你生活的一半时间都在实验室度过
You spend half your life in the lab.
我在流感恢复期
I was recovering from the flu.
我下周会重考  没什么大不了的
I'm retaking it next week. It's not an issue.
一般来说  我会同意物竞天择适者生存
Normally, I'd let darwinism run its course.
但是  卡迪对她的海报男孩
But Cuddy's in a big tizzy
快要被炒了的事紧张不已
about her poster boy getting canned.
那我们怎样才能让小矮个全力以赴呢
So how are we gonna get the short guy off the short bus?
-找个家教怎么样  -我不需要家教
- What about a tutor? - I don't need a tutor.
那就请家教吧
Tutor it is.
自选一味良药吧
Choose your poison.
如果你想畅饮澳洲啤酒
Chase, if you prefer pounding Aussie beers
并一起感慨悲剧的离婚生活的话  选奇斯
and commiserating over the suckiness of divorce.
如果你想了解精神能量  闪卡
Masters, if you want nervous energy,
以及各种可憎晦涩的知识竞赛  就选马斯特斯
flash cards and obnoxious pieces of arcane Trivia.
如果你需要被毫无幽默感的
Foreman, if you need to be berated
凶神恶煞训斥  就是福曼了
by a humorless hard-ass.
福曼吧
Foreman.
有意思
Interesting.
你心里肯定比看上去更焦虑不堪
You must be more worried than you look.
我需要会诊  威尔森医生
I need a consult, Dr. Wilson.
一周后如果还痒的话给我打电话
So call me in a week if it still itches.
谢谢
Thank you.
一定替我亲一下莎拉
And be sure to give Sarah a kiss for me.
一定
Will do.
莎拉是谁
Who's Sarah?
我估计是她的孙女
Her granddaughter, I think.
早期老年痴呆
Early stages of dementia.
你有什么要会诊的
What's the consult?
我需要你的医学意见
I need your medical opinion
决定我们晚上去哪个酒吧爽一下
on what bar we're gonna hit for happy hour tonight
庆祝自萨姆离开后
to kick off the official end
你自怜自艾三个月的正式结束
to your three-month pity party over Sam.
今晚不行
I can't tonight.
因为莎拉吗
Because of Sarah?
没错  就是我那痴呆病人的孙女
Yes, because of my senile patient's granddaughter.
被你抓包了  我有约了
You caught me. I'm busy!
莎拉是谁
Who's Sarah?
威尔森的朋友
Wilson's friend.
我电脑瘫痪了
My computer crashed.
关于他熟人的资料全都没了
Lost my database of his acquaintances.
或者你们俩都在骗我
Or you're both lying to me.
我完全不知威尔森有个叫莎拉的朋友
I know nothing about Wilson having a friend named Sarah.
满意了吗
Satisfied?
当然不
Nooo.
呕吐物的八种类型是什么
What are the eight types of vomitus?
如果你再问我一道复习题
I could show you four right now
我立刻吐其中四种给你看
if you ask me one more review question.
是你选的我
Hey, you picked me.
你说你想要凶神恶煞的
You said you wanted a hard-ass.
不  那是豪斯说的
No, House said that.
我假装同意省得他再跟我啰嗦
I pretended to agree to get him off my back.
我选你是因为
I picked you because I wanted the guy
我想要那种
who doesn't like getting involved
不会多管闲事的人
in other people's problems.
我是这样没错  但我以为是你不想遭受
Yes, I thought you'd want to skip
因被炒而带来的巨大耻辱才选的我
the massive public humiliation of getting fired.
所以你就把我当傻瓜看待吗
By treating me like I'm an imbecile?
我没问题的
I'm totally fine.
我第一次病理学认证考了A
I aced my first pathology boards.
过去几百年医学可是有了长足的进步
Medicine has come a long way in the last hundred years.
你知道...
You know...
我听说有个人
I heard of a guy
认识一个
who knew a guy
能提前拿到考题的人
who could get the exam ahead of time.
我是这么听说的
It was something I heard.
病历上说
Patient's file
她根据新的减肥食谱减了些体重  对吧
said she lost some weight on a new diet, right?
没错  她改吃素了
Yeah, she went vegan.
泻药也算素食吗
Are laxatives vegan?
怎么了
Hello?
你在哪
Where are you?
在停车场里
In the parking garage,
搜查威尔森的车
searching Wilson's car.
我们有答案了  镁中毒
We have an answer. Magnesium poisoning.
我们发现了大量的泻药
We found a pretty large stash of laxatives.
滥用可能导致高镁血症
Abuse can lead to hypermagnesemia.
我承认这真是...
I admit that's...
令人震惊的奇思妙想啊
Impressively outside-the-box thinking.
豪斯
House.
你还在吗  豪斯
You still there, House?
一切正常吗
Everything okay?
不
No.
刚刚的一瞬间  我以为威尔森
For a second, I thought Wilson
可能滥用药物
might have a drug problem.
但事实比这糟糕太多了
Turns out it's much, much worse.
好吧  我们给她输液
Okay...uh, so we push fluids
然后等她的肾滤出高镁吗
and wait for her kidneys to clear the hypermagnesemia?
那得等到天荒地老了  因为根本就不是
You'll be waiting a long time since that's not what she has.
她的血压和呼吸频率都正常
Her BP and respiratory rate are normal.
你们俩忙着
While you two were so busy
开动脑筋的同时
being impressively outside the box,
却忽略了真实情况
you missed the actual box.
奇斯和马斯特斯有结果了吗
Chase and Masters done yet?
11月16号  我喝了两瓶清啤
Two light beers, November 16th.
17号  相当大一杯葡萄酒
One really bad glass of Pinot on the 17th.
18号以后没再喝酒
Uh, nothing from the 18th.
你不该去美航局这样的地方工作吗
Shouldn't you be working for NASA or something?
你是说为什么我只是个服务员吗
You mean why am I just a waitress?
不  我不是说...
No, I didn't mean...
对不起  我...
I'm sorry, I-I-I-I...
没关系
It's okay.
能记住并不意味着
Remembering something is not the same
我就能理解
as understanding it.
我不是天才
I'm not a genius.
我热爱我的工作  我干得很好
I love my job. I'm great at it.
能让我的脑子忙不停歇
Keeps my mind busy.
你好  我是豪斯医生
Hi, I'm Dr. House.
你不排便
You are not pooping.
我的问题是  你也是个笨手笨脚的人吗
Question is, are you also a klutz?
这个  我猜我和大多数人差不多
Uh... I guess I'm no clumsier than most people.
你为什么要猜呢
What are you guessing for?
你过目不忘
You've got a perfect memory.
我听说你能记住数字  日期  行为数据
I was told there'd be numbers, dates, fireworks.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
让我们回到2008年
Let's go back to 2008.
滑倒  跌倒  绊倒加起来一共多少次
How many trips, stumbles, falls did you have?
十一次
11.
真管用啊
This really works.
太帅了
Cool.
2009年呢
How 'bout 2009?
十二次
12.
更酷了  去年呢
Even cooler. Last year?
二十次
20.
协调性丧失状况剧增
That's a big spike in discoordination.
如果再加上便秘的话就是早期帕金森症了
If you add the constipation, it's early onset Parkinson's.
给她做全套神经测试  开始用左旋多巴
Give her a full neuro exam, and start her on levodopa.
你未经允许就闯进我家
Oh, I'm so surprised you broke into my apartment
我好意外啊
without telling me.
什么事
What is this?
一次调解
An intervention.
展品一
Exhibit A.
一塑料袋假荆芥
A baggie filled with nepeta cataria,
也叫做...
Also known as...
那盒子里装的最好别是我想的那样
That had better not be what I think it is.
如果你是指你的新瘾君子女友  没错
If you mean your new junkie girlfriend, then yes.
豪斯
House...
好吧  我交代  我养了只猫
Okay, fine. I got a cat.
谜底揭晓了
Release the kraken.
我觉得你没有意识到问题的严重性
I don't think you appreciate the severity of your situation.
你正迅速接近
You are rapidly approaching
男性独身主义病的末期
an end-stage male spinsterism.
那只猫
That cat,
那只你负责注射胰岛素
that diabetic cat that you're shooting up with insulin
并喂食猫薄荷的糖尿病猫
and buying dime bags of catnip for,
意味着你彻底放弃寻找新对象了
that means you've given up on ever finding anyone.
你不觉得你在大惊小怪吗
Don't you think you're completely overreacting
如果是我大惊小怪  你干嘛骗我呢
If I'm completely overreacting, why'd you lie to me?
因为我就知道你会大惊小怪
Um, because I knew you would completely overreact.
你给它起名叫莎拉
Its name's Sarah.
这不是猫的名字  是女人的名字
Cats aren't named that. Women are.
搞什么飞机
What the freud is that about?
听着  不是我给她起的名字
Look, I didn't name her.
我邻居起的
My neighbor did.
她死了  我很难过
She died, and I felt bad.
要是她被收养所接去就完了
Sarah would have been destroyed at the shelter.
如果你不一天回家两次给它打针
Aww, who would want a cat that croaks
这只猫就会把嗓子嚎哑
if you're not home twice a day
这样的猫谁要啊
to shoot it up?
简直就是活生生的《迷失》[知名美剧]
It's like having your own button on Lost.
我很确定
You know, I'm pretty sure
附近有条河[话外音  可以淹死猫]
that there is a river nearby.
我要养她
I'm keeping her.
耸肩
Okay, shrug your shoulders
保持住
and don't let me push them down.
我忍不住想问
So I have to ask, uh...
你有什么诀窍吗
Is there a trick you use?
比如助记符号
Mnemonics?
比如冥想
Meditation?
不  没有诀窍
No, no tricks.
我毫不费力  真的  能力摆在那
I don't even try, really. It's just there.
我的记忆会因为
Is my memory gonna go away...
帕金森氏症而丢失吗
with the Parkinson's?
很有可能
It's quite possible.
但在作出最终诊断前
But we still have a lot of tests to do
我们还得做很多检查
before we have a definitive diagnosis.
也有可能是癌症
Well, here's hoping for cancer.
娜迪娅
Nadia?
你老板给我打过电话
Your boss called me.
打扰了
Sorry, um...
我是艾琳娜  娜迪娅的姐姐
I'm Elena, Nadia's older sister.
你没必要来这
You don't have to be here.
我愿意相信  如果我病了
But I'd like to pretend you'd visit me
你也会来医院看我的
if I were in the hospital.
你带了雏菊来
You brought daisies.
你最喜欢雏菊花了
They're your favorite.
不  我最讨厌了
No, they're my least favorite.
我的脸曾六次被它刺伤
I was stung in the face six times by--
天啊
Oh, god.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我的心脏
My heart.
心跳加快  宽波复杂性心动过速
Fast, wide-complex rhythm.
拿除颤器
Get the paddles.
心脏问题排除了帕金森氏症
Cardiac involvement rules out Parkinson's.
回到短期麻痹
We're back to transient paralysis
高肌酸激酶  再加上心律不齐
and high CK, plus arrhythmia.
马斯特斯  当你最终
Masters, when you finally
出落成女人时
blossom into a woman,
会睡一个养猫的男人吗
would you ever sleep with a man who had a cat?
当然
Sure.
错  答案是不会
Wrong, the answer is no.
小邋遢
Slut.
你们养过猫吗
Any of you ever had a cat?
那你们做过爱吗
Any of you ever had sex?
我想  这就是你们书呆子常说的
I think, as your people say,
证明完毕
quod erat demonstrandum.
儿茶酚胺过量会导致心律不齐
An excess of catecholamine could set off an arrhythmia.
不是嗜铬细胞瘤  她的血压很正常
It's not a pheo. Her blood pressure's fine.
很可能我们落下了明显症状
Maybe we're missing the obvious.
心脏问题可能是由多种原因引起的
The heart could be behind everything.
如果心脏不能有效泵血
If it's not pumping effectively,
肌肉会丧失功能
the muscles shut down.
肌酸激酶浓度升高  协调能力下降
CK elevates, coordination suffers.
你为什么要问猫的事
Why are you asking about cats?
好奇嘛
Curiosity.
我们能专心点吗
Can we focus here?
她的心脏问题
Uh, her heart problems
是在娜迪娅见到她姐姐时出现的
started when Nadia saw her sister.
紧张导致心率不齐
Stress-induced arrhythmia
可能是因长QT综合症而起
could be caused by long QT syndrome.
她姐姐进屋不过五分钟
Her sister was barely in the room five minutes.
她说她们已经六年不见了
She said they'd been estranged for over six years.
关系够紧张的
That's a lot of tension.
做个压力测试确认是否有长QT综合症
Run a stress test to confirm long QT.
这需要药物诱发
It'll have to be drug-induced.
跑步机会使她的缝针撕裂的
Treadmill will pull her stitches.
药物从来不是最好的解决方法
Drugs are never the answer.
如果我们想让她心脏发狂
If we want her heart to go crazy,
有更简单  安全的办法
There's something simpler and safer.
她姐姐
Use the sister.
你对我说谎
You lied to me.
没有  我说我不知道威尔森
No. I said I didn't know anything about Wilson
有个叫莎拉的朋友
having a friend named Sarah.
在豪斯的规则里  这不算撒谎
Under House rules, that is not a lie.
他很孤单
He's lonely.
猫能让他的感情有所寄托
That cat is a nice way for him to get some affection.
这么一只普通的猫
That's not the kind of putty tat
可不能让他得到慰藉
he needs to be getting it from.
他需要的是女人
He needs a putty tat he can tap.
为什么这事对你来说这么重要
Why is it so important to you?
在第二次离婚后
After divorce number two,
他不可遏制地坠入
he fell into a committed relationship
和一只三脚暹罗猫的爱河中
with a three-legged siamese.
不接电话
He stopped answering his phone,
重新把家装修的像个灰色花园
redecorated his place like Grey Gardens.
他不能回到正常的人类社会
He wasn't able to come back to humanity
除非为他留一扇
until a window was left
充满悬念通往冒险的大门
suspiciously and heroically open.
一只猫怎么能打开这扇窗户  我不知道
How that cat opened the window, I will never know.
他只是需要些时间
He just needs more time.
别去烦他和他的猫了
Leave him and the cat alone.
你插手我就撤退
I won't if you will.
抱歉我带了雏菊来
Sorry about the daisies.
我总搞不清楚你究竟喜不喜欢
I always get it confused if you love or hate them.
你想知道我告诉你我讨厌雏菊
Do you want to know exactly how many times
到底有多少次了吗
I've told you that I hate them?
我不是有意的
I didn't do it on purpose.
她的心跳没有加快
Her heart rate isn't moving.
她姐姐的刺激点火候不够
The sister stress pot needs stirring.
你想让我挑起争端吗
You want me to start a fight?
不
No.
小煽呼一下
Just agitate a little,
提些陈年往事
use something from the history.
你又不是去骗她们
You're not lying to them.
事实上  你既告诉了她们事实
In fact, you'd be telling the truth,
又为她们提供了医学需要的服务
and serving their medical needs.
你们俩有一阵子没见了  是吧
You haven't seen each other in a while, huh?
我听说你倒车撞娜迪娅的事了
I heard the story about the time you hit Nadia with the car.
一定很可怕吧
It must have been pretty scary.
你为什么要对他们说这事
Why would you tell them that?
他们问我骨折是怎么来的
They asked about broken bones.
我发誓我看过后视镜了
I swear that I checked my mirror.
你知道这是骗人的话
You know that's a lie.
你知道我在那取信
You knew I was getting the mail,
你根本不关心我  所以没看倒车镜
and you just didn't care enough to check!
正因如此  你还毁了我的23岁生日
Just like you didn't care that you ruined my 23rd birthday!
娜迪娅  你又来了
Nadia, don't start!
你来这假装很关心我  是你挑起的
You started by coming here, acting like you give a crap.
又要吵架了吗
Here we go again!
就因为我带了束雏菊  我就成坏蛋了吗
I'm such a monster because I brought daisies.
你  你现在得离开
You -- you need to leave right now.
好吧  她会没事吗
Well, is she gonna be OK?
艾琳娜  滚
Elena, get out!
你说十分钟就回来
You said you'd be ten minutes.
我不知道该买哪种奶酪
I couldn't decide on the cheese.
你什么时候才肯弄套公寓住
When are you getting an apartment?
或者住回原来的房子
Or at least a storage room?
之后会的
I'll get to it.
现在我挺喜欢这里的
I like it here.
他们有视频点播
They have video on demand.
我准备了一套模拟测试
I pulled a practice test.
我讨厌模拟测试
I hate practice tests.
我没看过《非常嫌疑犯》
Hey, I never saw the Usual Suspects.
开始复习前你想看看吗
You wanna check it out before we start?
你在干什么  我们就剩三天了
What are you doing? You've got three days.
为什么每个人都觉得
Why is everyone's first assumption
我会在这次白痴考试中不及格
I'm gonna fail this stupid test?
是有这可能  因为你上回就没过
Maybe, because you did.
那是因为我在感冒恢复期
I was recovering from the flu.
我才不管你是不是染上了埃博拉病毒
I don't care if you were dying from ebola.
你的得分不该在70分以下的
You shouldn't have gotten less than a 70.
你除了找借口和三心二意啥都不会
You're nothing but excuses and distractions.
这跟你的自以为是与感觉良好
Well, it's a nice match with your condescension
有的一拼
and superiority.
好好看电影吧
Enjoy the movie.
凯文·史派西就是恺撒·苏尔
Kevin Spacey is Keyser Soze.
她怎么样了
How is she?
我们给她用了β-受体阻滞药
We started her on a beta blocker.
这会控制好她的心率
It should keep her heart rhythm under control.
在我们做更多检查期间  她会保持稳定
She'll be fine while we run more tests.
你听到她不让我进屋了吗
Did you hear that she banned me from her room?
我知道我并不完美  但她也...
I know I'm not perfect, but she's...
她有时真是够混蛋的
Oh, she can be such a bitch.
她总是斤斤计较
She never ever ever let anything go.
请转告娜迪娅她不必担心
Tell Nadia she doesn't need to worry
会再见到我了
about seeing me again.
是我挑起了争吵
I started the fight.
我们需要她心跳加快  所以我激怒了你
We needed her heart rate to rise, so I provoked you.
你怎么能这么戏弄人
You can't play with people like that.
我可以向娜迪娅解释
Maybe if I explain to Nadia--
不  没用的
No, it doesn't matter!
她只会记得我们又多了一次争吵
It's just one more fight for her to remember.
我想你俩都是混蛋
Guess you're both bitches.
马斯特斯
Masters.
闻闻她的口气
Smell her breath.
呼气
Breathe out.
氨气
Ammonia.
什么情况
What is it?
我想你的肾脏开始衰竭了
I think your kidneys are shutting down.
衰竭的肾脏说明
Failing kidneys puts the heart
她的心脏问题是一种症状
back on the list as a symptom.
可能她吃素
Maybe she went vegan
是因为她失去了蛋白质的味觉
because she lost the taste for protein.
可能是淀粉样变性
It could be Amyloidosis.
那在做细胞核观察时看到的应该是硬化的心肌
We would have seen a stiff heart on the nuclear study.
自身免疫系统疾病可以造成
But autoimmune could account
多重器官衰竭和麻痹
for multiple organ systems and paralysis.
还有很多其它可能
There are a number that'd fit.
格林巴利综合症  多肌炎
Guillain-barre, polymyositis.
多发性硬化  结节性多动脉炎
Ms, polyarteritis nodosa--
系统性红斑狼疮
SLE.
为什么给我这些
Why are you giving me these?
因为  他们在做那些检查时
Because, while they're off running all these tests,
你得填好这些保险表
you will be submitting the insurance forms.
整个部门的人都可以填啊
There's an entire department for that.
完全正确  福曼的部门
Exactly. The Foreman department.
只有你福曼  福曼
of which you are the Foreman. Foreman.
我知道你有空
I know you got the time.
一只小袋鼠[指奇斯]告诉我你最近
A little Wallaby told me that you recently
辞职不做陶博的救世主了
vacated your post as Taub's savior.
-他严刑逼供  -你比马斯特斯还烂
- He asked. - You're worse than masters.
我做错什么了
How's this my fault?
他不需要老师
He doesn't need a tutor.
他需要利他林和保姆
He needs ritalin and a babysitter.
把保险表当作动力吧
Consider the forms incentive.
陶博不过的话
Taub doesn't pass,
他会成为你生命中永远的痛
he'll become a permanent part of your life.
这跟卡迪没关系  是吧
This isn't really about Cuddy, is it?
是你
It's about you.
你不想失去我
You don't want to lose me.
我觉得你在乎我
I think you care.
别以为你恶心我
Don't think you can disgust me
我就会把福曼撤掉
into pulling Foreman off you.
暂停其它  给她类固醇来治疗自身免疫
Pulse the patient with steroids for the autoimmune.
给她做透析缓解肾脏衰竭
Start her on dialysis for the kidney failure.
给陶博鄙视和耳光
Treat the Taub with insults and small slaps
来治疗他的顽固
for the obstinacy,
开始注射"学习"来缓解大脑失灵
And start him on studying for the brain failure.
不  不行
No, that's not gonna work.
我四点要去理发
I have a haircut at 4 o'clock.
我会去上班...
I'll be in the offi--
我二十分钟后到办公室
I'll be in the office in about 20 minutes.
好的
Yeah, okay.
你对我的公寓动了手脚
You planted something in my apartment
好让我以为自己对莎拉过敏
to make me think I'm allergic to Sarah.
妄想症是弓形虫病的首要症状
Paranoia is the first sign of Toxoplasma gondii,
肯定是你当了"疯狂的猫夫人"染上的
the parasite linked to crazy cat lady disease.
我并没有妄想
I'm not paranoid.
我对豚草和蒲公英过敏
I'm allergic to ragweed and dandelion.
而不是对猫过敏
I'm not allergic to cats.
你是想误导我
You're trying to gaslight me.
说不定你潜意识里
Maybe your subconscious is afraid
害怕自己会孤独终老
that you're gonna die alone.
结果表现为胡言乱语还狂打喷嚏
And it just comes out as gibberish and sneezing.
不然就证明是我反应过度了
Prove that I'm overreacting.
今晚咱们俩出去
Boys' night out.
去查理酒吧好好享受一番
Good time Charlie's.
他们刚改过广告标语
They just changed their slogan to,
"浪荡女子堕落天堂"
"Where the trashiest ladies get trashed."
你不觉得这么做很虚伪吗
You do see the hypocrisy in all this, don't you?
就在不久前  你还过着放任自流的生活
Until recently, your lifestyle of choice was self-exile.
但我从来不养猫
But I never had a cat.
要不晚上八点来接我吧
Why don't you pick me up at 8:00?
你还需使用一轮类固醇
You're gonna need another round of steroids.
同时  我会开始对你进行透析
In the meantime, I'll start your dialysis.
我听说艾琳娜可能会再过来
So I heard Elena might be coming back.
你觉得我...
You think I was...
对她态度太糟了吗
too hard on her?
我们都会记仇
Well, we all hold our grudges.
我这不是怨恨
It's not a grudge.
而是常识
It's common sense.
就是简单的算术
It's simple math.
她对我的伤害多过帮助
She's hurt me more than she's helped me.
绝大多数人会扭曲他们的记忆
Most people edit their memories.
他们会加些无伤大雅的小谎
They add small, little lies
这样就不用面对事实的真相
so they don't have to face the truth.
但我的记忆始终保持原样
My memories remain the same.
我记忆中的事实不会改变是因为
My truth never changes, because...
我的记忆就是事实
my truth is the truth.
所以任何人都得不到你的原谅吗
So no one ever gets forgiven?
这样生活岂不是很孤独
Sounds like a lonely way to live.
不  我会原谅别人
No, I-I do forgive.
只要他们做的好事...
As long as the good things they do...
超过
outweigh...
我  我无法呼吸了
I can't, I can't breathe.
怎么了
What?
没有  我只是
Nothing, I just...
一直想象你的家里会铺长绒地毯
always pictured your place with shag carpet.
就像那种
Like kind of a
《卧底侦查队》里用的
Mod Squad vibe.
不是因为你是黑人的关系
Not because of the black thing.
我只是一直以为你更...
I always thought you were more of...
你只能在这间房和马库斯的旧屋里活动
You're limited to this room and Marcus's old room.
马库斯去哪了
Where's Marcus?
据他说  正在佛罗里达给叔叔干活
He tells me he's working with our uncle in Florida.
据他说
He tells you?
你不许盯着任何不属于你的东西看
You don't look at or touch anything
也不许碰  包括食物
that doesn't belong to you, including food.
你老实的学习  睡觉
You will study and you will sleep.
考试前  都不许离开我的视线
And you will not leave my sight until the exam.
行  那我明早天亮了再回来
Great, I'll be back bright and early tomorrow, and...
这事已不仅仅关系到你的未来
This is no longer just about your future.
也影响到我的前途
It's about mine, too.
要是你考砸了  我绝对不会放过你
You fail, and I will kill you.
出现呼吸窘迫说明
Respiratory distress means
不是自身免疫疾病
we were wrong about autoimmune.
可能是肾衰竭导致的肺水肿
Could be pulmonary edema from renal failure.
肺水肿不会引起荨麻疹[过敏引起的]
Pulmonary edema doesn't give you hives.
你觉得这是过敏反应吗
You think this is an allergic reaction?
不可能  她体内注满了类固醇
It can't be. We pumped her full of steroids.
如果这过敏非常棘手  是有可能的
It can be. If it was a really, really bad one.
有好消息也有坏消息
I have good news and bad news.
好消息是  我对你的诊断是正确的
The good news is I was right about
你患有某种自身免疫病
you having some autoimmune disease.
你只是对透析过敏
You're just allergic to the dialysis.
但如果我不能进行透析
But if I can't have dialysis
而我的肾又在衰竭
and my kidneys are failing,
岂不是说我就要死了
won't that mean I'll die?
你已经知道坏消息是什么了
Well, you figured out the bad news.
那我们怎么办
What do we do?
我们换个病例诊治
We look for another case.
即便你对自身免疫病的诊断是正确的
Even if you're right about autoimmune,
我们眼下也没有时间去证明
we now don't have time to prove it.
移植委员会是不会给她一个肾脏的
The transplant board will never give her a kidney.
也许我们不需要他们批准
Maybe we could go around them,
找她的亲属捐献
get a relative to donate.
哪个亲戚啊
Which relative?
你是说那个转身离开
The sister who walked away
还告诉你"绝不会回来"的姐姐吗
and told you she was never coming back?
你明知道这是我们害的
We caused this, you know.
她们的确不和  但我们把情况变得更糟
They were estranged, but we made it worse.
早在我们干涉前她们的关系就没回转的余地了
That relationship was broken long before we got there.
娜迪娅实际上量化了她们的关系
Nadia literally keeps score.
她把所有的事都计算得很清楚
She tallies everything.
她觉得艾琳娜
She decided Elena's done
对她的伤害多过帮助
more bad things to her than good,
不值得她再投入感情
Doesn't deserve her affection.
我确定她没错
I'm sure she's right.
和世上的其他人不一样
Unlike everybody else in the world,
她的记忆力让她得以
her memory seems to let her keep
用绝对客观的眼光
a pure and objective view
看待与她相处的人
of people in realtionships.
不会因为个人的偏见和纠结的过去
There's no petty emotions or agendas
蒙蔽了双眼
fogging the windshield.
这有什么错
Why is that so wrong?
因为这使她要在205号病房
'cause it's making her die alone
孤独地死于肾衰竭
of kidney failure in room 205?
并不一定
Not necessarily.
娜迪娅的姐姐跟她不一样
Nadia's sister's not like her.
我肯定她是受主观情感支配的
I'm sure she's got plenty of subjective emotions
我们可以好好利用
we can exploit.
你干嘛不化内疚为动力
Why don't you go channel your guilt,
看能不能让她捐个肾出来
see if you can get her to cough up a kidney?
我吗  我不是很擅长这种事
Me? I'm not good at that type of thing.
应该让其他人去
Someone else should go.
这事是你搞砸的
Someone else didn't screw this up.
不是我
I didn't!
别说你不过是奉命而为的替罪羊
You were just obeying orders, right?
自己解决这个问题
Go fix this.
什么嘛
What..
我的本意不是让你们仇视对方
I didn't mean to make you hate her.
而现在她的肾衰竭了  我...
And...now that her kidneys have failed, I--
我一直以来都是个书呆子  只会直线思考
I've a always been a book and equations person.
人们总是自寻烦恼
People are problematic.
随心所欲  乱七八糟
And...random and messy.
而和姐妹相处
And with sisters...
我是说我有个非常亲密的表妹
I mean, I had a cousin who I was close to,
当我们的生理期撞在一起
and when our menstrual cycles synced,
就跟在角斗士学校一样
it was like gladiator school--
你是想让我给她捐一个肾吗
Do you want me to donate a kidney to my sister?
是的
Yes.
好的
Okay.
真的吗
Really?
这么做也不一定能改善你们的关系
It might not fix your relationship.
我好像不该提这个
Probably shouldn't have said that.
左边  注意你的左边
Your left, on your left.
别发牢骚了
Stop whining already.
我正要换成狙击枪
I was getting a sniper.
休息时间还剩五分钟
Five minutes left in the break.
但过了冷却池就到下一关了
But the next level's just past the cooling tanks.
刚才说好的  休息之后
That was the deal. We take this break,
你做一份模拟题
you do a practice test.
其实  我没有感冒
I-I didn't have the flu.
我就是  发挥失常了
I just...choked.
你每天都在做出生死抉择
You make life and death decisions every day.
你可是在豪斯手下干活
You work for House.
你压力一直很大  可从未却步退缩
You're under constant pressure, and you never choke.
在初次病理学学会的考试中我拿了满分
I got a perfect score on my first Pathology Boards.
我一直在想  "无论我这次得分多少
I kept thinking, "Whatever my score is now,
"都会成为衡量现在的我
"it's going to be a measure of the distance
与过去的我之间差距的标杆"
between me and the man I used to be."
你不能再这样自我施压了
You gotta stop psyching yourself out.
上次考试是在
Well, the last test was before
我失去妻子和家庭之前
I lost my wife and my home,
所以我肯定下一次会好得多
so I'm sure the next one will go much better.
有时  我半夜醒来
Sometimes, I wake up in the middle of the night,
之后就辗转难眠
and I can't sleep for hours
因为我担心自己的诊断出了错
'cause I'm worried I got the diagnosis wrong.
船到桥头自然直  没事的
These things work out.
我们找到一个捐献人
We found a donor.
是你姐姐
It's your sister.
我想你应该知道这个
Just thought you should know.
娜迪娅  能听到我说话吗
Nadia, can you hear me?
麻醉的药效正在退去
You're coming out of your anesthesia.
你会觉得有点醉晕
You're gonna feel a bit groggy.
你表现很好
You did great.
看上去情况不错
Everything's looking good.
娜迪娅  醒一醒
Nadia, come on now.
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes.
给我三毫克氯羟去甲安定
Three milligrams of lorazepam,
还需要吸引器
and I'm going to need suction.
痉挛发作说明类固醇没有用
Seizures mean the steroids aren't working.
测验结果也出来了
And we got the tests back.
我们错了  不是自身免疫病
We were wrong. It's not autoimmune.
可能是急性间歇性卟啉病
Could be acute porphyria.
没有腹部疼痛
No abdominal pain.
病人有没有感谢她姐姐
Did the patient thank her sister?
没  至少现在还没
Not yet, at least.
看看结果会如何
See if she will.
你想知道什么
What are you trying to find out?
她是否实话实说
If she's telling the truth.
她声称自己在用客观的眼光看现实
She claims she objectively sees reality.
通过权衡善恶来评判别人
Weighing the good and bad in people.
如果真是这样
If that's true,
我觉得不管她姐姐曾有多少次
I don't care how many times her sister
不问自取地用她的发带
borrowed her scrunchie without asking,
给她捐肾应该能化解一切
a free kidney ought to trump all the bad stuff.
如果不是这样呢
And if it doesn't?
那说明她和我们一样  是烂人一个
That means she sucks, like the rest of us.
我们还没考虑过血液疾病
We haven't considered her blood.
血管凝块会引发腿部  心脏
Clots could hit her leg, heart,
肾脏和脑部问题
kidney, and brain.
凝血因子V Leiden基因突变
Factor V Leiden.
如果是这样的话  是最容易治疗的
Easiest to treat, if we're right.
给她用肝素开始治疗
Start her on heparin.
记得问她要不要感谢她姐
And ask for the thank-you.
我答得怎么样
How'd I do?
挺不错
Great.
不错
Great?
怎么个不错法
How great?
我答错了几道
How many did I miss?
数字并不重要
It's not about the numbers.
别...
Don't...
才答对了54%
54%?
模拟题总是要比
Th-they make the practice tests harder
正式考试难
than the actual exam.
我的天  我在你客厅里也不能正常发挥
Oh, my god, now I'm choking in your living room.
这样不行
This isn't gonna work.
你要给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
我找到一个人
I found the guy.
他肯卖我试卷副本
He can sell me a copy of the test.
我知道这是作弊
I know it's cheating,
我做人也很失败
And I suck as a person.
但明天早上就要考试了
But the test is tomorrow morning.
这不是作弊的问题  这关乎你的自信
It's not about the cheating. It's about your confidence.
你一旦作弊了  自信就再也找不回来了
You steal that test, and you'll never get it back.
我没法面对人生中的再一次失败了
I can't handle failing at one more thing in my life.
你是个好医生
You're a good doctor.
我很清楚你的能力
I've seen what you're capable of.
反映迅速  大胆而果断
You're fast, you're decisive, and you're bold.
有这种能力的人
And those are not the qualities of someone
是绝不用偷试题的
who needs to steal a test.
对于考试内容  你早就了如指掌
There is nothing on it that you don't already know.
你只需认识到自己的能力
You just need to know that you know it.
继续讲
Keep talking.
这个团队缺你不可
We need you on the team.
所以我们要坐在这  再做套模拟题
So we're gonna sit here and take another practice test
我们就不停地练习
and we're gonna keep taking them
直到你把它搞定
until you've kicked its ass!
你能行的  听到了吗
You can do this! You feel me?
是的
Yeah.
感觉跟杀人毁尸回来似的
I feel like we just buried a hooker in the desert.
长风破浪会有时
There'll definitely be another time
直挂云帆济沧海
to rise up and turn things around.
你会好起来的
You'll come back from it.
下次吧
Next time.
感觉如何
How are you feeling?
没任何好转
N-not any better.
血栓溶解需要一段时间
It'll take some time for the clots to resolve.
你姐姐恢复得很顺利
Your sister's recovering well.
如果你真是在计较善恶
If you're really adding up the good and bad...
我可以见她吗
Can I see her
太胖
Too fat.
太瘦
Too thin.
太饥渴
Too desperate.
不够饥渴
Not desperate enough.
你也来评头论足嘛
Come on, you can insult them too.
我看不必
I'd rather not.
现在批判个彻底
If you objectify them now,
待会儿你把她们绑在地下室桌子上
you'll feel more comfortable when you...
会感觉自然很多
tie them to a table in your basement later.
其它花招也行
Or whatever.
好吧
Okay.
腋下脂肪太多
Too armpit fatty.
那个  太正点
Whoa! Too hot.
我认识她
I actually know her.
她是咖啡屋的新服务员
She's the new barista at my coffee shop.
正在攻读经济学硕士
She's getting her Masters in finance.
胸大有脑
Brains and boobs.
一座富矿
The mother lode.
可惜服务员当得特烂
Total moron as a barista, though.
不论我点什么饮料
Every drink I order
她都给我加奶泡
ends up with whipped cream on it.
嘱咐她不加都不管用
Even when I say no whip.
姑娘  意思是人家喜欢你
Girlfriend, that means she's into you.
好吧
Okay.
你好  我叫威尔森  詹姆斯·威尔森
Hi, there. Wilson. James Wilson.
我是医生
I'm a doctor.
希望以上信息足够
I'm hoping that's enough to close,
因为我是社交白痴
because I'm also a social moron.
我还养了只猫
And I have a cat.
她说她想打奶泡的
She said my coffee is not the only thing
可不止是我的咖啡而已
she'd like to put whipped cream on.
但她的确对你有意思吧
Yeah, but is she interested.
酒保
Bartender!
每人一杯香槟
Champagne for everyone!
谢谢你
Thank you.
救了我一命
for saving my life.
我爱你
I love you, you know.
我刚想起了
I was thinking about those times
我们曾一起去斯波福德湖过暑假
we went up to Spofford Lake in the summer.
每次划独木舟
Whenever we took out the canoe,
都是你替我系好救生衣
you'd tie up my life vest for me.
下午带我溜进储藏室
In the afternoon, sneak me into the lodge
一起偷冰棍
so we could steal popsicles.
或许我们可以和好如初
Maybe we could go back.
我可以开车去  我们住一间小屋
I could drive us up there. We could get a cabin and...
还可以租独木舟
And maybe rent a canoe.
我好久没想起过
Oh, wow, I haven't...
斯波福德湖
thought of Spofford in...
娜迪娅
Nadia...
你没事吧
Are you okay?
艾琳娜  对不起  我做不到
Elena, I'm sorry! I can't do this!
停一下
Can you stop?
停下别推我
Just stop pushing me for a minute.
我现在懂了
I understand now
你为何在餐馆打工
why you stuck yourself in that diner,
远离家人朋友
away from friends, away from family.
你无法原谅任何人
You can't forgive anyone.
我认为你不是在权衡
I don't think you weigh anything.
你只是跟多数人一样
I think you're like a lot of people.
对不开心的往事耿耿于怀
You focus on the bad memories
忘记了欢乐
instead of the good.
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
娜迪娅  把手在腿上放一下
Nadia, put your hand in your lap for a moment.
-我没动  -我知道
- I'm not doing that. - I know.
这是一种无意识动作  叫做舞蹈病
It's an involuntary movement called choreia.
说明什么
What does it mean?
说明我们仍然不知道你的病因
It means we still don't know what's wrong with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
据你所知  威尔森之前喜欢的那个急诊护士
Do you know if that... O.R. Nurse that Wilson liked
有没有跟男友分手
ever broke up with her boyfriend?
你的威尔森痴迷症不是过去了吗
I thought your Wilson fetish was over.
我得找好备胎
I'm putting together a second string
以防大胸服务员那边进展不顺
in case things don't go well with the well-breasted barista.
你不能总管着他
You've gotta let that guy alone.
他不该没人管
He's not supposed to be alone.
这就是你心结所在
Is that what this is about?
威尔森孤身一人你却有了伴儿
You feel guilty because
所以你有负罪感是吗
Wilson's the one that's alone and not you?
你仍然认为自己不配得到幸福
You still don't think you deserve this.
你才知道我吗
Have you met me?
你的幸福并不是他不幸的原因
Your happiness doesn't take his away.
心安理得是可以的
It's okay to enjoy it.
舞蹈病  排除了血液凝固功能失常
Choreia. Rules out the clotting disorder.
我们又回到了原点
Means we're back to square one.
如果病症已发展到脑部
If it's hit her brain,
说明她时间不多了
that could mean she doesn't have long.
那么现在的问题是
So then the question becomes,
她姐姐会参加她的葬礼吗
will the sister show up at the funeral?
她试图与姐姐和解
She tried to reconcile,
但是糟糕的回忆占了上风  她退缩了
but the bad memories crowded out the good, and she ran.
人无完人
Nobody's perfect.
还有什么
What else?
我们需要的信息她都有
Come on, the woman has all the information we need.
她本身就是一座诊断库
She's a bottomless diagnostic library.
或许我们忽略了她住处的信息
Maybe we're missing something from the apartment.
生活方式方面的
Some lifestyle thing.
有道理  她拼了几百幅拼图
Yeah, it's all muscle strain
造成肌肉拉伤
from doing her hundreds of Jigsaw puzzles.
我们应该重做核磁共振
We should do another MRI.
脑出血会...
A brain hemorrhage would...
多少幅拼图
How many puzzles?
好吧  我刚才有点儿夸张
Okay, I was exaggerating.
几十幅
Dozens.
做周边血涂片
Do a peripheral blood smear.
找棘红细胞
Look for acanthocytes.
我马上就到
I'll be right in.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
开个玩笑
Just kidding.
喜欢拼图游戏
So...Jigsaw puzzles.
拼图能让我心平气静
Um, I find them calming.
有没有半途而废的
You ever left one unfinished?
没有  不拼完我会抓狂
No, that would drive me crazy.
说到抓狂...
Speaking of...
你为什么动它
Why are you doing that?
更重要的问题是  你又是为什么呢
More important question is, why are you?
只是习惯而已
It's just a habit.
这是一种强迫性的习惯
It's a habit that compels you in an obsessive way
已经成了一种病
that's so bad, it's a disorder.
我没有强迫症
I don't have OCD.
强迫症患者有不同的表现方式
Each brain with OCD has its own way of filtering it.
有些人不停洗手
Some people wash their hands
贮存电视报
and hoard TV guides.
你则玩拼图  贮存记忆
You do puzzles and hoard memories.
所以我们以为是天赋的记忆
So what we thought was a gift...
不过是你对自己生活经历的强迫回忆
Is just you literally obsessing over your own life.
所以我才无法控制我的记忆
That's why I can't stop the memories,
怎样努力都不行
even when I try.
但是其它症状呢
But everything else?
我的肾脏
My kidneys?
记忆问题只是更严重疾病的症状
Memory was just a symptom of a symptom
的表症之一
of a larger disease.
你有麦克劳德综合症
You have McLeod syndrome.
是一种罕见的遗传障碍
It's a rare genetic disorder
会影响神经系统和血液
that affects the nervous system, the blood.
并且会引起
And can cause...
强迫症
OCD.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
此病无法治愈
It can't be cured.
但你的症状
But your various symptoms
可以通过药物控制
can be managed with medication.
最乐观估计
Best-case scenario,
你还可以再活二十年
you can live another 20 years.
安慰你一下
If it's any solace,
死亡面前  人人孤独
everybody dies alone.
看来没安慰到
It probably isn't.
考得如何
How'd it go?
知道所有答案
Well, it's hard to choke
想考砸都难
when you have all the answers.
这样想吧
Look at it this way.
考试考得烂
It's better to suck at taking one test
总比没本事救人强
than to suck at saving people's lives.
瑞秋嫌它太大
Uh, Rachel thought it was too big,
我又不能把它抬去旅馆用
and I can't keep it in my hotel room.
你要送给我吗
You're giving it to me?
就你原来那电视
I couldn't stand the thought
怎么带人回家
of you having company over with that other TV.
我都觉得丢人
It's embarrassing.
谢了
Thanks.
该我谢你
Thank you.
那个
Hey, look, um...
我这儿有空屋
I have the room.
你愿意的话  可以住下
You could stay, if you wanted to.
找好房子再搬
Just until you find your new place.
你走了谁跟我打游戏呀
Who else am I gonna play savageskate with?
不住在一起也可以联机玩嘛
We could do that online from separate houses.
你能不能闭嘴
Will you shut up?
能
Okay.
感觉如何
How you feeling?
好多了
Much better.
我不相信豪斯说的话
I don't believe what House said.
我想豪斯自己如今也不一定拿捏得准
I'm not sure even House believes it anymore.
你之前说你那个样子
You said you didn't have a choice
是因为别无选择
to be the way you are.
现在你有选择的机会了
Now you do.
这是选择性五羟色胺再摄取抑制剂
These are SSRIs.
治疗强迫症比较有效
They've been effective in treating OCD.
我会失去记忆吗
You mean lose my memory?
不是全部记忆
Not lose it entirely.
只是会变得跟其他人差不多
It'll just become more like anyone else's.
我的记忆力
My memory...
是唯一能让我
is the only thing
与众不同的东西
that has ever made me special.
或许如此
Maybe so.
但与众不同的代价
But if you want to be special...
就是顾影自怜
you're gonna have to be alone.
那是我给莎拉准备的
Those are for Sarah.
下毒了吗
Are they poisoned?
下毒...
Poi...
你的被害妄想症啊
you and your paranoia.
失陪一下
Now, if you'll excuse me...
我该把豚草放得更保险一些才好
I really should find a better place to store my ragweed.
好意我心领了
It's a very nice gesture,
但它还在我公寓里
but it's still in the apartment.
我要听
So...I wanna hear
你与咖啡浪女
all the dirty, dairy-specific details
激情浪漫的所有细节
of your night with java the slut.
好吧
All right.
首先
First of all,
绝对真实
all real.
其次
Second...
她是真正的极品
A true connoisseur
精通...
of the dark arts of...
我临阵脱逃了
I flaked.
送她上车然后说了晚安
I walked her to her car and said good night.
我会继续努力的  我...
I will get back into it, I...
你得再给我点时间
you just need to give me a little more time.
我给你十天
I'll give you ten days.
行
Fine.